<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recommendations on EarthCube Software Citation</title>
    <link>/recommendations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recommendations on EarthCube Software Citation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/recommendations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>For Software Developers</title>
      <link>/recommendations/fordevs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/recommendations/fordevs/</guid>
      <description>SOFTWARE DEVELOPERS There are three basic recommendations for software developers or maintainers of primary code repositories. The intent of these recommendations are to provide an unambiguous mechanism to signal to the user base that the software you are providing is intended to be cited and that there is no room for interpretation for your citation and software license.
  Create a persistent web identifier (such as a Digital Object Identifier (DOI)) for your software so that it can be appropriately traced, tracked, cited and maintained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Software Users</title>
      <link>/recommendations/forusers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/recommendations/forusers/</guid>
      <description>SOFTWARE USERS Cite the software you use Whether created by you or somebody else software needs citation. The more software is cited, the more likely its creators will be acknowledged for the contribution their software has made to research, applications or wherever it is used.
Use consistent information in your software citations The ESIP citation guideline suggests your citation minimally include title, version, publication year, PID, Publisher, author, URL and access date as shown in this example:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>